http://www.nexustreatment.org/privacy-policy

Nexus Family Healing Privacy Policy
Nexus Foundation for Family Healing respects the privacy of all donors and prospective donors and believes in safeguarding their personal information.
Our policy explains our practices regarding the collection of information from donors and prospective donors, including from our website, that can personally identify them and/or their organization, and the choices they can make about the way their information is collected and used.
Consent to Privacy and Donor Contact Policy:
By using our website or by providing personal information to us, an individual signifies agreement with the terms of our current Privacy and Donor Contact Policy as posted on our website. Individuals who do not agree with any term in this Policy, should not use our website or provide any personal information to us.
Information We Collect from Our Donors and Prospective Donors
We collect and use various pieces of information from persons donating to Nexus Foundation for Family Healing, Nexus Family Healing, and its affiliates. For example, this information may include the amount donated, the date of the donation, the donor’s name, address, telephone number, directions from the donor concerning the donation, the donor’s e-mail address, the donor’s credit card information, or a copy of the donor’s check received. The Internal Revenue Code and regulations require us to keep certain donor information as part of our records. We also collect certain information from prospective donors who may volunteer their contact information to us by, for example, registering for an event or requesting information from our website. We collect information from our donors and prospective donors on events they have attended, publications they have received, and special requests they have made for program information. We also collect information provided by donors and prospective donors in the form of comments and suggestions. This information is maintained in a secured database, and only authorized personnel have access to this information for appropriate business purposes.
How We Use the Information We Collect:
We will use information provided to us by donors and prospective donors for these purposes only:
• To distribute receipts for donations;
• To thank donors for their donations;
• To include the names of our donors in publications (such as an annual report), when applicable, which may be available in print and on our website; provided, that the names of donors who request that their gift be received anonymously will not be published in such publications;
• To inform donors and prospective donors about program updates and outcomes, news, special events, funding requests, and upcoming activities for Nexus Foundation for Family Healing, Nexus Family Healing, and its affiliates;
• For internal analysis and recordkeeping; and
• For compliance reporting purposes with the Internal Revenue Service and various state governmental entities.
Nexus Foundation for Family Healing works closely with Nexus Family Healing and its affiliates, and information about donors and prospective donors may be shared among our network of programs and organizations to facilitate effective and efficient communications. For example, we may use this information to make more accurate budget projections, to understand donors’ interests in our mission, and to plan future events and activities.
No Sharing of Personal Information or Financial Information:
We will not share, sell, rent or lease donor or prospective donor information to other organizations. The identity of donors requesting to remain anonymous will not be shared publicly. The financial information of our donors is accessible only by professional staff to process this data. We do not share our donors’ financial information, including credit card account information, except as necessary to process a transaction. When donors choose to make a donation by credit card, we submit this information directly to a secure credit card processor.
Choice to Opt Out:
We provide all donors and prospective donors with the opportunity to opt out of having personal information collected or used for certain purposes. If an individual no longer wishes to receive communications from Nexus Foundation for Family Healing, Nexus Family Healing, and/or its affiliates, they may opt out of receiving communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in email communications from us, or by contacting us at:
Nexus Foundation for Family Healing
505 Highway 169 N Suite 500
Plymouth, MN 55441
763-551-8656
NFF-Foundation@nexusfamilyhealing.org
This does not include any data we are required to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
External Links to Third Party Websites:
Our website may contain links or references to other parties’ sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or other practices of any such outside sites and expressly disclaim any and all liability related to such sites. We encourage individuals to read the posted privacy policy whenever interacting with any website.
Cookies
Many websites, including ours, use cookies, which are pieces of numeric data stored on the user’s computer so that we can identify a user when they return to our website. We can only "read" cookies that are placed on a user’s computer from our own website. Usage of cookies is not linked to any personally identifiable information. A user can select to disable cookies by changing browser settings. If a user chooses to disable cookies in your browser, they will not be able to access portions of our website content.
Notice to Parents; Compliance with Children's Online Privacy Protection Rule ("COPPA"):
We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. Users under 13 are asked to not attempt to send any information about themselves to us. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible.
Donor Bill of Rights
Nexus Foundation for Family Healing adheres to the Donor Bill of Rights.
STAY CONNECTED
To learn more about Nexus Family Healing, sign up now!
